疑犯追踪 第1季 第5集
person.of.interest.s01e05.720p.hdtv.x264
字幕翻译：YYeTs人人影视
你在被监视着
You are being watched.
政府有一套秘密系统
The government has a secret system.
一台机器
A machine.
每时每刻都在监视你
It spies on you every hour of every day.
我知道  因为它是我造的
I know because I built it.
我设计这台机器是为了侦测恐怖行动
I designed the machine to detect acts of terror,
但它却看到了一切
But it sees everything.
与普通人相关的暴力罪行
Violent crimes involving ordinary people.
像你一样的普通人
People like you.
而政府认为这些罪行无关紧要
Crimes the government considered irrelevant.
他们不肯作为  所以我决定插手
They wouldn't act so I decided I would.
但我需要一个搭档
But I needed a partner.
一个有能力介入其中的人
Someone with the skills to intervene.
因为被当局追捕
Hunted by the authorities,
我们只能秘密行事
We work in secret.
你永远找不到我们
You will never find us.
不管你是被害人和行凶者
But victim or perpetrator,
如果你的号码被列出来
If your number's up,
我们就会找到你
We'll find you.
是我
Yeah?
有麻烦了
We've got a problem.
这儿什么好吃
What's good here?
这没用  里瑟先生
That won't work, Mr. Reese.
什么没用
What won't?
你提问的方式
Your interrogation technique.
这儿什么好吃
What's good here?
我就单纯地问个问题
It's an innocent question.
你什么时候单纯过
No question is ever innocent from you.
你是想判断我是不是这里的常客
You're trying to determine whether I come here often.
然后再根据这点
Armed with that knowledge,
查出我的住处
you'll try to figure out where I live.
芬奇  你太多疑了
You're paranoid, Finch.
我多疑不是没道理
With good reason.
也许我就是不清楚这家店什么好吃
Maybe I just don't know what's good here
所以才随便问问
So I'm asking the regular.
好好吃饭吧  里瑟先生
Enjoy your meal, Mr. Reese.
萨缪尔・盖茨
Samuel Gates.
你名单上的下一个号码
The next number on your list.
校车来了
Bus is here!
我们知道他什么情况
So what do we have on him?
生于南波士顿
Born in south Boston.
纽约大学法学学位
Law degree from NYU.
和他儿子萨姆住在上西区
He lives on the upper west side with his son, Sam.
他老婆呢
Where's the wife?
去年去世了
She died last year.
和盖茨有关吗
Any chance Gates was involved?
除非他能让老婆患上癌症
Not unless he found a way to give her cancer.
伊丽莎白・盖茨去年四月
Elizabeth Gates was diagnosed
被确诊为脑瘤  无法手术
with an inoperable brain tumor last April.
十一月就离世了
By November she was gone.
那他就剩这个宝贝儿子了
So the son is all he has left.
-等等  -差点忘了午餐
- Wait! - Oh, don't forget your lunch.
保姆那边什么情况
What do we know about the nanny?
克里斯蒂娜・罗哈斯
Christina Rojas.
盖茨在老婆患病时就雇了她
Gates hired her when his wife fell ill.
小家伙很喜欢她
The kid sure likes her.
她没少陪这孩子
She spends a lot of time with him.
根据她的收费钟点看
Judging by the hours she's billing,
盖茨多数时间都在办公室
I'd say Gates was putting in long days at the office.
爱妻离世
He lost the woman he loved.
他大概想借工作摆脱痛苦
Probably threw himself into his work to cope.
他办公室在哪儿
Where's his office?
纽约刑事法院
Criminal court, city of New York.
也许就是因为这点
Which may explain why the machine
机器才报出他的社保号码
has sent us his social.
绝对不行
Absolutely not.
这是合法获取的直接证据
This is direct evidence, properly obtained.
所以他应该是目标  而非嫌犯
So odds are he's the victim, not the perpetrator.
法官常受死亡威胁
Judges get plenty of death threats.
法官大人  这个录像不符合均衡原则
It doesn't pass the balancing test, your honor.
其证明效力...
The probative value is--
我知道什么是均衡原则  律师先生
I know what the balancing test is, counselor.
盖茨比常人遭遇更多死亡威胁
Gates gets more death threats than most.
换句官话就是
Word at the courthouse is
他以一己之力向罪恶展开战争
He's waging a one-man war on crime--
强硬  一丝不苟  树敌无数
Tough, by-the-book, making lots of enemies.
如果案发现场的视频也有不公平的偏见
If video of the actual crime is unfairly prejudicial,
那恐怕我们就得摒弃
I think we might have to give up
整个陪审团机制了
on the entire concept of trial by jury.
视频资料有效
The video's in.
每个人都有敌人
Everyone has enemies.
机器会选出恶意和伤害的预谋
The machine identifies malice and an intent to harm.
我们得判断究竟是什么威胁
We need to determine which threat it saw,
哪一个才是真的威胁
Which one is real.
在搞清情况前
Until we know,
最好的办法就是盯紧盖茨
my best bet is to stay close to Gates,
以防被人占了先机
In case somebody makes a move.
看来他的敌人真是不少
Looks like he's got quite a collection of enemies.
里瑟先生  有威胁迹象吗
Mr. Reese, any sign of a threat?
胆固醇算吗
Does cholesterol count?
恐吓信基本分析完了
I'm nearly done analyzing the threatening letters.
还有九封查不到来源
There are nine that I still can't source,
不过找到六个可疑嫌犯
But I've identified six possible suspects.
里面有留平头的白人吗
Any of them white guys with crew cuts?
没注意到
Not that I'm aware of.
庭审中  放心  [9分钟前发送]
已放学  行动  [6分钟前接收]
芬奇  那孩子叫什么来着
Finch, what's the son's name again?
小萨缪尔・盖茨
Samuel Gates, Junior.
怎么了
Why?
我看我们跟错了萨缪尔・盖茨
I think we've been following the wrong Sam Gates.
克里斯蒂娜
Hey, Christina.
你肯定不相信
You're not going to believe
马克今天对盖泽尔老师说什么了
what Mark C. Said to Mrs. Kizer today.
靠错误的信息我可没法准时赶到
I can't be there on time if I'm getting bad information.
机器跳出的号码不会错
The machine did not send us the wrong number.
盖茨法官肯定有危险
If it says that judge Gates is in danger, then he is.
那他的儿子呢
Well, tell that to his son.
绑架必定与此有关
The kidnapping must connect.
可能这是他们阴谋的一部分
It could be the first step in a larger plot
最终以法官被害收场
That ends with the judge dead.
我们还是可以阻止这一切
We can still put a stop to it, all of it.
只是需要个计划
But we need a plan.
计划我有
I have a plan.
找到萨姆
Find Sam.
法官刚死了老婆
The man just lost his wife.
不能再让他孤寂而终
I won't let him wind up alone.
盖茨法官
Judge Gates.
-爸爸  -萨姆
- Dad? - Hey, Sam.
爸爸...
Dad...
怎么了
What's wrong?
他很好  法官大人  眼下还好
He's fine, your honor... for now.
你是谁
Who are you?
我儿子在哪儿
Where is my son?
不许报警
No cops, no feds.
说出去他就死定了
Tell anyone and he's dead.
老实等着  晚上会给你电话
Keep quiet and you'll hear from us tonight.
等等  听着  我们可以解决这事
Wait, look... we can handle this ourselves.
想要什么只管说
Just tell me what you want.
我是萨姆  留言吧
This is Sam, leave a message.
克里斯蒂娜  我是盖茨法官
Hi, uh, Christina, this is Judge Gates.
求你回个电话
Please! Call me back.
你好  我是盖茨法官  萨姆和丹尼尔在你那吗
Hi, uh, this is Judge Gates. Is Sam there with Daniel?
没啊  怎么了
No, is everything okay?
上帝啊
Oh, god.
我们想办法把你儿子找回来
Let's figure out how we get your son back.
你是谁
Who are you?
我是来帮你的
I'm here to help you.
萨姆在哪儿
Where is Sam?
我儿子在哪儿
Where is my son?
你和劫匪一伙的吧
You're with the kidnappers, aren't you?
你是他们的人
You're one of them.
不  我试过阻止他们
No, I tried to stop them.
不过劫匪联系你了
But the kidnappers made contact.
这很好
That's good.
就是说他们想谈判
That means they want to negotiate.
只要你儿子有价值  他们就不会伤害他
They won't hurt your son as long as he's worth something.
你试过阻止他们  是什么意思
What do you mean, you tried to stop them?
你当时在场吗
You were there?
是的
I was.
只可惜到晚了
But not soon enough.
你怎么就知道他们要绑架我儿子
How did you know they were going to take him?
你到底是谁
Who the hell are you?
现在你有两个问题要问
You have two questions right now:
"你是谁"  "我儿子在哪儿"
Who are you and where is my son?
你觉得哪个比较重要
Which one do you want to focus on?
他们来过我家
They were in my house.
他们怎么避过警报装置
How'd they get past the alarm?
我监听了你的电话
I've tapped your phone
现在你家门前的街上装个监控
and I'm setting up surveillance on your street.
这是搞清劫匪身份的最好方法
It's our best shot at IDing the kidnappers.
克里斯蒂娜哪儿去了
Where's Christina?
我儿子放学后她就该在
She was supposed to be here when he got home.
我没看到她
I didn't see her.
她可能是内鬼吗
Could she be in on it?
不可能
That's impossible.
她爱萨姆
She loved Sam.
法官...
Judge...
你受到过绑架威胁吗
Have you received any kidnapping threats?
或者判过涉及绑匪的案子
Tried any cases involving kidnappers?
我银行里有30万
I have about $300,000 in the bank.
要是他们要钱  我可以出
If this is about money, I can pay.
不管他们什么企图  我都会找到你儿子
Whatever this is about, I'm going to find your son.
把他带回家
And I'm going to bring him home.
在这待着  等下个电话
Stay here and wait for the next call.
他们说了  不许报警
They said no cops, no FBI.
可他们没说不能找我
They didn't say anything about me.
好吧  芬奇
Okay, Finch.
盖茨电话的音频和家门口
You should have audio on his landline
大街的视频你应该有了
and video of the street outside Gates' house.
和你一样  我也想救那孩子
I want to save that boy as much as you do,
可你记住  里瑟先生
but remember, Mr. Reese--
我们不能让一个法官问及
We don't need a judge asking questions
我们是谁  我们做的事情
about who we are and what we do.
眼皮底下的绑架我都搞不定
I can't work a kidnapping from arm's length.
等我把萨姆找回来  再担心盖茨的事吧
I'll worry about Gates once we get Sam back.
绑匪那边有什么情况吗
Where are we on the kidnappers?
那个电话有查到什么吗
Any luck tracing their call?
恐怕没有
I'm afraid not.
那个IP地址是网络上的匿名旁白
It was voice-over I.P., anonymized through the internet.
那另一个电话呢
what about the other phone?
被盯梢的扔进垃圾桶的那个
The one the spotter threw in the trash?
显然是一次性电话
it's a disposable, obviously.
记忆卡上查不到什么
Not much on the sim card.
只有些电话记录和短信息
Some disconnected numbers and a handful of texts,
但都设了密码
All equally cryptic.
所以我准备黑进到电话公司
So I'm trying to hack the cell company
进一步查找信息
For more information.
但他们的防火墙太难攻破了
But their firewall is impressive.
居然能难倒你
you can't get in?
你不是造了监视整个国家的机器吗
You built a machine that spies on the entire country.
当时为政府工作
when you work for the government,
权限当然不成问题
Access is not a problem.
今非昔比好吗
Things are different now.
我想办法搞定
I'll figure it out.
那就快点搞定
Well, figure it out quick.
绑匪还杀死了保姆
The kidnappers killed the nanny.
他们一定是逼她说出了防盗门的密码
They must have gotten Gates' alarm code out of her.
911  请问有什么紧急情况  喂
911 emergency, hello?
-看到卡特了吗  -没有
- Hey, you seen Carter? - No.
你好
Detective.
好
弗斯科  你是从51区调过来的吧
You came down from the 51st right, Fusco?
布朗克斯分局
The Bronx finest.
怎么想到来这
What brought you here?
想换换环境
I wanted a change of scenery.
是想换
Wanted?
还是不得不换
Or needed?
你到底想说什么
You got something you want to say?
我听到些让我担心的传言
I heard some rumors that got me concerned.
我只是想多了解下我的同事
I just like to know what I'm dealing with.
卡特  既然你这么友好
Carter, I'm going to buy you a coffee.
那我给你买杯咖啡去
Since you've been so nice.
加奶不加糖
Cream, no sugar.
随叫随到
Oh, he comes when he's called.
表现不错
Good.
如果你不再想干掉我  那就完美了
Now if I could just train you to stop trying to kill me.
我还得在这儿工作多久
How long am I going to have to work down here?
上下班太不方便了
Commute's a bitch.
别抱怨了
You should be grateful.
不是所有人都能调到特遣队
Takes some guys years to make task force.
而且  还有我罩着你呢
Plus, I let you live.
卡特查得怎么样了
Carter, is she getting close?
我只知道
All I know right now
你惹了个不好惹的角色  伙计
Is you pissed off real police, my friend.
她不抓住你不会罢休
She's not going to stop till she got you.
说完了吗
Is that it?
做下弹道测试
Ballistics.
再查查看有没有
And find out if there's been
为赎金的绑架案记录
Any ransom kidnappings reported.
平头白人
White guys with crew cuts.
其中一人长发
One with long hair.
绑架可是大新闻
Kidnapping's big news.
如果有我肯定知道
I'd have heard something.
那有没有安珀警戒
What about amber alerts?
当国内确认发生儿童绑架案时  透过各种媒体向社会大众传播的一种警戒告知
诱拐儿童
Child abduction?
我们要查这个吗
Is that what we're dealing with?
什么我们
We?
我们啥时候成一国的了
Since when are you on board?
这关系到一个失踪的孩子
It's still a missing kid.
不管我做过什么  我至少还是警察
Hey, whatever else I've done, I'm still a cop.
你需要帮助  我义不容辞
If you need some help, you let me know.
知道了吧
You understand?
我破了电话公司的防火墙
I cracked the cell company's firewall.
那个盯梢的手机是用现金
The spotter's phone was purchased with cash
以假身份购买
And a phony name.
但绑匪总得睡觉吧
But our kidnappers have to sleep somewhere.
手机的定位数据显示
The location data puts this phone
这人每晚都呆在布鲁克林的一个街区
On the same block in Brooklyn every night--
富兰克林和威斯街交口14号
14th between Franklin and Wythe.
那我这就去会会他
Then I'll hit him where he lives.
芬奇
Finch.
我找到了那家伙
I just found our guy.
他招了吗
Is he talking?
现在还不行
Not at the moment.
莱昂・约瑟夫・特斯基  结尾是"夫"
Turski, Leon Josef, with an "F".
慢着
Hold on.
芬奇  我知道是谁绑架了萨姆
I know who has Sam, Finch.
沙亚卡・普斯科夫・泽万――SP-9
Szajka Pruszkow Dziewiec: SP-9.
一支凶残的东欧街头混混团伙
It's a nasty street gang from eastern Europe.
你以前和他们打过交道吗
You dealt with them in your former employment?
他们和普什图军阀有生意往来
They were trading with the Pashtun Warlords.
用枪交易海洛因
Guns for heroin.
但他们也在华沙做绑架勾当
But they also run kidnappings in Warsaw.
看来他们还把业务拓展到纽约来了
Looks like they just opened up a new branch in New York.
来吧  我们去溜一圈
Come on, let's go for a ride.
我要的就这些  警探
That's all I need, detective.
谢谢
Thank you.
我是凶案组的卡特  收到了你的信息
Carter, homicide, I got your message.
我是奥尔森警探
Detective Olson.
我收到了你的信息
I got your bolo.
白人男性  1米88  鬓角灰白  西装革履
White male, 6'2", graying temples, nice suit.
临时工说看见他离开  就在报警电话拨通那会
Super said he saw him leaving at the time of the 911.
有电话录音吗
Did you get audio on the call?
录什么音  都没人说话
What audio? Nobody said boo.
检验医生说她两小时前就死了
M.E. Said she was dead two hours before.
那你觉得那人是凶手吗
So you think your guy killed her?
不  我觉得是他报的警
No, I think he called 911.
这下好了  她是从波多黎各偷渡来的
Great, she's F.O.B. from Puerto Rico,
没家人  没男友
No family, no boyfriend.
天哪  真是送来个烫手山芋啊
Man, I thought you were going to gift wrap this for me.
她做什么工作
What kind of work does she do?
她给西区一家人当保姆
Oh, she was a nanny on the west side.
已经派人去联系她的雇主了
We've got unis talking to her clients.
如果那人不是凶手  他来这干什么
So if your guy wasn't the shooter, what was he doing here?
克里斯蒂娜被人杀了
Someone killed Christina?
天哪
Oh, god, I--
萨姆回来的时候她就不在
She wasn't here when Sam came home.
萨姆是谁
Sam?
我儿子
My son.
我儿子放学回来时她就不在
She wasn't here when he came home from school,
所以他给我打电话
So he called me.
我就赶回家陪他
I came home to be with him.
他正在楼上玩儿
He's upstairs playing right now.
法官大人  感谢您的配合
Thanks for your time, judge.
克里斯蒂娜之前...
Christina was, um...
她...
She was, uh...
在伊丽莎白去世时就陪在我们身边
With us the night that Elizabeth died.
她对萨姆很好
She was so good with Sam.
她还只是个孩子
She was just a kid.
他还活着  好吗
He's alive, okay?
只要萨姆还有利用价值  他们就不会杀他
As long as they need him, Sam's still alive.
你也说不准
You don't know that.
法官大人  你得帮我
I need your help, judge.
你听说过沙亚卡・普斯科夫  SP-9吗
Have you ever heard of the szajka pruszkow, sp-9?
你到底是什么人
What are you?
退役的警察吗
An ex-cop?
还是调查局的人
FBI?
我有过类似的经历
I have experience in situations like this.
你只要知道这个就行
That's all you need to know.
是吗
Yeah?
或许你一个人解决不了问题
Well, maybe you're not enough.
或许我该把那警察叫回来
Maybe I should call those officers back
告诉他实情
And tell them the truth.
我知道如何不打草惊蛇
I know how to be invisible.
而警察和调查局探员没法办到
The police and the fBI don't.
但不管怎样我都会救出你儿子
But I'm going after your son regardless.
现在告诉我  你听说过SP-9吗
Now, have you ever heard of a gang called sp-9?
没有
No.
他们是谁
Who are they?
是他们打来的
That's them now.
喂
Hello?
你一个人吗
You're alone?
是的
Yes.
你得证明我儿子还活着
I need proof that my son is alive.
让他听电话
Put Sam on the phone.
爸爸
Dad?
萨姆...你没事吧
Sam... are you hurt?
爸爸  救我  我想回家
Dad, please, I want to go home!
萨姆
Sam, Sam!
别急啊  法官大人
Relax, your honor.
你儿子在这里很好
Your son is just fine.
他是个好孩子
He's a good boy.
跟你一样聪明
Smart, like you.
你要多少钱
How much?
你要什么我都给你
I'll pay anything you want.
看吧
See?
我就说你聪明
Smart.
但算你走运  我们不要钱
But, fortunately for you, we don't want your money.
我们想要你帮忙
We want your help.
你现在处理的一个案子
There's a case in your court right now,
是安琪拉・马汉的案子
The people vs. Angela Markham.
我要让检方败诉
The people... are going to lose.
什么
What?
法官  撤销原案
Throw the case, judge.
让安琪拉・马汉被判无罪
Angela Markham walks.
不然你儿子就没命了
Or your son dies.
安琪拉・马汉
Angela Markham?
她在停车场撞伤了人
She mowed down some guy in a parking garage.
不过是个简单的肇事逃逸案
It's a simple hit and run.
她现在却是找到你儿子的关键
Well, now she's become the key to finding your son.
安琪拉・马汉是贸易中心附近
Angela Markham is an account exec
一家科技公司的账户经理
At a tech company near the trade center.
六周前  她在退休欢送会上喝醉了
Six weeks ago, she got drunk at an office retirement party,
开车出车库时撞了一位会计师
And hit a CPA on her way out.
她以酒驾和过失杀人被起诉
Charged with DWI and vehicular manslaughter.
不过是个偶然的车祸
It's just a random accident.
这个女人和
What does this woman have to do
绑架我儿子的人有什么关系
With the people who took my son?
我不知道
I don't know.
但他们并不只是想杀死萨姆
But it's not just Sam's life they're playing with.
他们也要杀掉你
They're planning to kill you too.
你怎么知道
How can you know that?
你从哪得到的信息
Where are you getting your information?
我的信息渠道绝对可靠
Let's just say I have a source and it's never wrong.
跟这些人没法讲道理
Look, these people can't be reasoned with.
他们不可信任
They can't be trusted.
如果我们要救你儿子
If we're going to save your son,
我要找出能打击他们的方法
I need to find a way to hurt them.
30分钟后就要继续开庭
The trial resumes in 30 minutes.
我该做什么
What do I do?
拖延时间就行
Just stall.
假装你在跟他们合作
Make it look like you're cooperating.
但你得给我争取时间
But buy me time.
这明显不是街头混混
Well, this isn't a street gang.
这是跨国团伙
This is a multinational corporation.
SP9起码在世界上18个国家都有活动  范围遍布欧亚
SP-9 is active in at least 18 countries in Europe, Asia--
自从国际刑警拿下了曾经的普斯科夫黑手党后
After Interpol took down the old Pruszkow Mafia,
他们就长进了
They got smarter.
开始掩盖纹身
Started hiding their tattoos,
学起了军事化管理  电脑
Studied military discipline, computers--
几乎找不到他们的数据残留
They have almost no digital footprint.
我还在找任何能找回盖茨他儿子的线索
I have yet to find anything that could help us find Gates' son.
那就重点查她
Then focus on her.
这女的跟那帮派千丝万缕
Somehow this girl and that gang connect.
我敢打赌  睡她的男人
My best guess, whoever she's sleeping with
肯定是SP9里的高层
Is high up in sp-9.
我赌她男朋友知道萨姆被关在哪
Bet her boyfriend knows where they're keeping Sam.
对了我去查那女的  那你去干什么
And while I'm checking into the girl, what'll you be doing?
追查余下的那帮人
Tracking down the rest of them.
我有史以来撬开人嘴巴的记录是16小时
The longest it's ever taken me to break someone is 16 hours.
你看起来不像有要我打破纪录的样子
You don't look like you're going to set a record.
想说话了吗
Want to talk?
你肯定喜欢窝在里面
You must like it in there.
新案子
Caught a fresh one?
我那穿西装的伙计帮我找到了另一个案子
My guy in a suit led me to another case.
布朗克斯的一位保姆午餐休息时被杀了
Nanny from the Bronx murdered on her lunch break.
枪手挖走了弹头
Shooter dug the slugs out, huh?
只有这枚
Just the one,
而且我不确定那是枪手所为
And I'm not so sure that was the shooter.
是我前妻  我必须得接这电话
It's my ex, I've got to take this.
你掐时间的能力真是强到令人发指啊  老兄
You've got a real creepy sense of timing, man.
弹道报告  警探
Ballistics report, detective.
下坠式
Squat.
你的那枚弹头没进警局系统
Your slug's not in the system.
我相当肯定卡特在研究你的罪案现场
And I'm pretty sure that Carter's working your crime scene.
这个死掉的保姆
Hey, does this dead nanny
跟失踪的小朋友有关系吗
Have anything to do with the missing kid?
我还要东西时候会给你电话
I'll call when I need something else.
你现在需要一切你能用到的协助
You need all the help you can get right now.
我是说  如果我能找出那个保姆杀手
I mean, if I can I.D. The nanny killer,
或许能帮到你找那个小孩
It might help you with the kid.
我有说错吗
Am I wrong?
我会给你我的联系方式
I'll give you a way to contact me.
及时跟我汇报情况  还有别让卡特碍手碍脚
Keep me posted and keep Carter out of my way.
这是什么状况
So what have we got?
初步判定是情感破裂
Primary's thinking romance-gone-bad,
但是一般这种情况都会很乱
But those are always so messy.
这个现场太干净了
This is too clean.
看看这个枪伤射入口的边缘
Look at the circles on this entrance wound.
你能想到几个气昏头的男朋友
How many pissed-off boyfriends you know
会去买消音器
Go out and buy a silencer?
还情感  情感个球
Romance, my ass.
凶手是职业杀手
Your killer is a pro.
搬把椅子过来做
Pull up a chair.
安琪拉・马汉
强制配对成功
起立
All rise.
由尊敬的盖茨法官大人主审
The honorable Judge Gates presiding.
请坐
Be seated.
由公众对诉安琪拉・马汉
In the matter of the people vs. Angela Markham,
现在开庭
Court is now in session.
莱昂
Hey, Leon.
旅途愉快不
How's the ride back there?
现在
Now...
你可以吃这个美味的汉堡
You can have this juicy burger,
或者咱再多来几圈
Or you can go for another spin.
你只需要帮我找个吓坏了的小男孩
All you have to do is help me find a scared little boy.
我不知道他在哪  我发誓
I don't know where he is, I swear to god.
谁是安琪拉・马汉  她跟SP9又有什么关系
Who's Angela Markham and what does she have to do with sp-9?
没听过这人
Never heard of her.
我说  我不知道他们为什么想要那孩子
Look, I don't know why they wanted that kid.
你都不知道是吧
You don't know much, do you?
他们就是这么活动
That's how they run it.
他们常常小组活动  有机小组
They work in small teams. Cells.
你的组里都有谁  给我全名
So who's in your cell? Full names.
我们只用诨号相称
We only use street names.
AK  克拉科夫  索普  宅人
A-K, Krakow, Sops, Ziom.
一共四个人  我就知道这些
Look, there's four guys, that's all I know.
现在求你放我出去好不好
Now would you please let me out of here?
什么都没给我就想出来
For no names and no info?
不是  不是  不是  慢  慢  慢
No, no, no. Wait, wait, wait.
别  等等
Okay, wait.
我知道个地方
I know a place.
洛里默街3185号
It's 3185 Lorimer.
我就是去那个地方拿钱
It's where I go to get paid.
很好
Good.
你这叫我怎么吃啊
How am I supposed to eat it?
你自己搞定
You'll figure it out.
我观察到一辆白色SUV以高速横冲直撞
I observed a white suv driving erratically at high speed.
我估计是酒后驾驶  于是就上去拦截了
I stopped the vehicle for a possible DWI.
当你接近那辆车时候你看到什么
And what did you see when you approached the car?
血迹
Blood.
左前轮的挡泥板上
On the front left fender.
反对  上述事实不能作为证供
Objection, facts not in evidence.
反对有效
Sustained.
那车子看起来什么样
Uh, how did the vehicle look?
前后有损伤
There was front end damage.
看起来疑似血液的红色液体
A red fluid that appeared to be blood--
反对  法官大人
Objection, your Honor.
反对有效
Sustained.
然后发生了什么
What happened then?
辩方走出了车辆
The defendant got out of the vehicle.
她看起来醉酒或服用药物
She appeared to be intoxicated.
反对
Objection!
反对有效
Sustained.
-法官大人  -律师
- Your honor--  - Counselor...
我现在给你些时间
I'm going to give you some time
好让你的证人再准备准备
To better prepare your witness.
明天上午十时继续
Resume at 10:00 A.M. Tomorrow.
盖茨法官
Judge Gates.
我很失望  法官大人
I'm disappointed, your Honor.
你怎么知道我在这
How did you know I was here?
是她告诉你的吗
Did she tell you?
安琪拉・马汉到底是你什么人
Who is Angela Markham to you anyway?
你是不是不想要你儿子回家了
You don't want your son back, is that it?
让我跟他说话
Let me talk to him.
等你不再拖时间了再说
Not until you stop stalling.
听好
Look...
我只能这么做  否则地检官会上诉
I have to do this right or the D.A. Can appeal.
你想她重获自由
You want her free,
我就得确保她保持如此
I have to make sure she stays that way.
做事要对
Do it right.
动作要快
And do it fast.
还有别忘了你耍花样的代价
And don't forget what you're playing for.
我们没时间了  里瑟先生
We're running out of time, Mr. Reese.
你查出关于安琪拉的情况了吗
Did you dig up anything on Angela?
跟你讲话这会我都在过滤她的通信录和邮件
Going through her contacts and emails even as we speak.
帮派那边怎么样
Any progress with the gang?
我从莱昂・特斯基那边要到了个地址
I got an address from Leon Turski.
这就过去
On my way now.
已经差不多了
It's as good as done.
怎么  你以为我傻啊
What, do you think I'm stupid?
我没获得自由撤销罪名之前都不算完
It's not done until I'm free and clear.
你这样就没意思了
This is bad for business.
我的客户不耐烦了
My clients are asking questions.
那不是我的问题
That's not my problem.
你才是问题
You are the problem.
我们整个行动都危在旦夕
Our whole operation is in jeopardy
就因为你多喝了几杯
Because you had too many shots.
除非你认识有人能干我干的活
Unless you know someone who can do what I do,
否则交易继续
Our deal stands.
一旦你撤销了罪名  我就回去工作
Once you get the charges dropped, I go back to work.
一切照常
Business as usual.
那孩子在哪
Where's the boy?
我不知道
I don't know!
芬奇
Finch...
刚找出来一个能打击他们的办法
Just found a way to make these guys hurt.
还不去找  给我去找是谁拿了
Well, find it and find out who took it.
我手下有两个人失踪了  外加五十万的钱
I am missing two men and $1/2 million.
有人在搞我们
Someone is making a move against us.
我要知道是谁
I need to know who!
通知你们的组员
Contact your teams!
改变计划
Change of plans.
我想我知道了为什么他们不要钱了
I guess we know why they didn't ask for money.
除了这个我那还有六个这样的包
I have six more just like it.
可以作为我们跟他们讨价还价的筹码
Could be our bargaining chip to get Sam.
放这些的地方可能还有更多
There may be lots more where these came from.
安琪拉没有跟绑架犯上床
Angela's not sleeping with our kidnapper.
我认为她在跟他做交易
I think she's in business with him.
她供职的那家技术公司
That tech company she works for,
他们做银行软件
They make banking software.
能监控洗钱的那种
The kind that can spot money laundering.
我刚好发现一间满是小额钞票的房间
And I just found a room full of small bills.
09年的时候  她监督了一州银行
In 2009, she oversaw the installation
反洗钱系统的全部安装过程
Of a new anti-money laundering system at Onestate Bank.
如果她仍有权限的话
If she still has access,
她按下鼠标就能关掉整个系统
She could turn that whole system off with the click of a mouse.
于是SP9就能利用世界最大的银行之一
Then sp-9 uses one of the biggest banks in the world
来洗白黑钱
To clean its dirty money.
他们不会留下任何数据残留
They leave no digital footprint
因为这就是他们付钱的方式
Because this is how they pay for things.
汽车  律师  安全屋
Cars, lawyers, safe houses.
如果我们能够接触到这些账户
If we can access those accounts,
我们有的就不只是谈判筹码了
We'll have more than a bargaining chip.
我们就能找到小萨姆
We'll have a way to find Sam junior.
他们知道我在拖延时间了
They know I'm stalling.
我们快了
We're getting close.
只要再拖住一小会就行了
Just need to hold off a little longer.
我给过你机会了
You had your chance.
我不会再拿我儿子的性命冒险了
I'm not playing games with my son's life.
他们一旦得逞就会做掉你们俩灭口
They'll kill you both as soon as they get what they want.
眼下  我能救你儿子
Now, I can save your son.
你必须相信我
You just have to trust me.
根据进一步的复核
Upon further review,
我要收回录像有效性的定论
I'm reversing my decision on admissibility.
法官大人
Your honor!
这段录像不符合均衡原则  律师
It doesn't pass the balancing test, counselor.
这会对陪审团做出对马汉女士的判决产生误导
This video would unfairly bias the jury against miss Markham.
那我要求审判无效
Then I move for a mistrial.
拒绝
Denied.
盖茨法官
Judge Gates--
律师上前
Approach.
你有问题吗  律师
Is there a problem, counselor?
恕我直言  大人
Respectfully, sir...
这到底是怎么回事
What the hell is going on?
再说一句话你就是藐视法庭
One more word and you are in contempt.
必要的话我会控告你行为不检
I'll have you charged with misconduct if I have to.
相信我  拉米雷兹女士
Trust me, miss Ramirez.
你不知道我会到什么地步
You have no idea how far I'll go.
没有之后了
Nothing further.
检方结束了
Prosecution rests.
这是账户数据
That's account data.
是绝密的
It's confidential.
不再绝密了  我们被黑了
Not anymore, we just got hacked.
什么  防火墙怎么被破了
What? How did they get past the firewall?
我在解决
I'm working here.
你叫什么  你是谁
What's your name? Who are you?
你的系统崩溃
Considering they called me
而他们通知我来弥补
When your system was compromised,
我想我大概是抢了你饭碗的人吧
I'd say I'm the guy that just took your job.
现在去医院会好受点
A hospital would be nice about now.
孩子在哪
Where's the boy?
我说了  我不知道
I already told you, I don't know.
那你们老大的名字呢  这你总知道吧
How about your boss's name? You know that yet?
我有家人  你也要杀了他们吗
I've got a family. You going to kill them too?
因为我要是说了他就会杀了他们
Because he will.
见过两只猫被塞进袋子里吗
You ever see two cats in a bag?
什么
What?
你想出来吗
You want out?
把老大名字套出来
Get your boss's name.
卡特
Carter.
过来  我想我有发现了
Come here, I think I got something.
我又去那个保姆住处查了下
I did another canvass
发现那里附近有个酒店
and I found a bodega near the Nanny's house
有对着马路的摄像头
With eyes on the street,
而这是纽约警局的监控录像
And it's on the NYPD surveillance feed.
就在谋杀发生的时候
This is right around the time of the murder.
看这个
Look at this.
长发的白人
White guy, long hair,
在脱手套
Pulling off gloves.
他可能就是凶手
He could be our killer.
也可能人家只是手冷了
Or just a guy with cold hands.
你怎么确认那个长发的就是凶手
What makes you so sure mr. Longhair is our man?
你有我不知道的信息吗
You get a description I don't know about?
我就是这么感觉
I got a hunch.
我查他车牌号想查他名字
I ran his plate to get a name,
结果查到个公司名
But I got a company instead.
科菲尔股份公司
Coldfield Holdings.
就在布鲁克林
It's in Brooklyn.
值得一查
Worth a look.
芬奇  我搞到个名字
Finch, got a name for you.
亚雷克・科斯卡
Jarek Koska.
据说他是老大
Word is he's the boss.
如果是他  那他这人很谨慎
Well, if he is, he's careful about it.
没有账户是他的名字
No accounts in his name.
这个行动规模很大
The operation is massive.
每天早上五点
Every morning at 5:00 a.m.,
安琪拉会将州银行的软件关闭三分钟
Angela shuts down Onestate's software for three minutes.
数以万计的钱神不知鬼不觉地流入银行
Millions of dollars flow in undetected.
SP-9不光是自己洗钱
SP-9's not just laundering their own money.
他们还有几百名客户
They have hundreds of clients.
肯定都是犯罪分子
All criminal themselves, I'm sure.
如果科斯卡用的是个皮包公司
If Koska's using a shell corporation,
那得花上一番功夫才能查出来
It could take hours to find it.
杀害保姆的凶手
与科菲尔股份公司有关联
芬奇
Finch?
查查看科菲尔
Try Coldfield.
显然名下有很多账户
Definitely a large account.
看来这些钱被用来购买...
Looks like the money's being used to buy...
游船  飞机  房产
Boats, planes, real estate...
大多都在纽约
Most of it right here in new york.
就是他们  把名单列出来
That's them, get a list.
萨姆可能就在其中一个地方
The place they're holding Sam will be on it.
我把地址发给你了
I'm sending you an address.
有栋房子  离盖茨家不到十个街区
A building less than ten blocks from Gates' house.
安琪拉上庭两天前刚刚被买下
Purchased just two days before Angela went on trial.
如果我能找到萨姆  法官就不用撤销原案了
If I can find Sam, the judge won't have to throw her case.
那你最好快点
Well, you better move fast.
安琪拉的陪审团已经有裁决了
I think Angela's jury just reached a verdict.
芬奇  如果我四分钟内没联系你就报警
Finch, if you don't hear from me in four minutes, call 911.
告诉他们萨姆的事  叫他们派人过来
Send them here and tell them about sam.
请起立
Please rise.
陪审团有裁决了吗
Has the jury reached a verdict?
是的  法官大人
We have, your honor.
裁决是什么
What say you?
没找到萨姆
我们认为辩方
We find the defendant...
无罪
not guilty on all charges.
如果你想要回你儿子  一个人来
If you want your son back, come alone.
不准带手机  GPS和武器
No cell, no gps, no weapons.
如果我看到除你以外的人
If I see anyone who's not you,
你儿子就死定了
Your son dies.
这么说安琪拉・马汉无罪了
So Angela Markham walks,
而盖茨法官也正要去送死
And judge Gates is heading to a death sentence.
机器既然报出了他的号码
The machine sent us his number
就说明他们不管怎样都准备杀了他
Because they were planning to kill him all along.
他和他儿子
Him and his son.
焦土战术
Scorched earth policy.
清理现场  毁尸灭迹
Clean up and cover their tracks
只要他们的目的达到了
As soon as they get what they want.
我们得警告他
We need to warn him.
我警告过了  他不听
I've tried. He won't listen.
但我们得有所行动
But we have to do something.
是的
We are.
你好  安琪拉
Hello, Angela. -
我要见我儿子
I want to see my son!
爸爸
Dad!
萨姆
Sam!
不
No!
我会给你机会道别
I'll let you say good-bye.
听着  我现在来了
Look, you've got me.
我满足了你的要求
I did what you asked.
你的所有要求
Everything you asked.
你就冲着我来
You can keep me,
但求你放了我的儿子
But please let my son go.
抱歉
Sorry.
法官大人
Your honor.
住手
Stop!
你的名字叫亚雷克・科斯卡
Your name is jarek Koska.
你的银行账号是1278340102
Your bank account number is 1278340102.
去年一年里你替你的客户
Last year you laundered
洗钱数量共计四百万美元
At least $400 million to clients
你的客户包括MS13  锡那罗亚毒帮
Including MS-13, the Sinaloa Cartel,
MS13: 发详于美国洛杉矶Pico-Union区的有组织犯罪集团
还有朝鲜政府
And the government of north korea.
你都是从这个酗酒的婊子那问来的么
So you got some info from that alcoholic bitch.
你也没法再告诉其他人了
I'm the last one you'll ever tell.
人数对你不利啊
These aren't good odds for you.
我不是单枪匹马
I'm not alone.
这里的每一个子儿
Every last dime has been transferred
都被转到一个海外账户下
To an offshore account.
照我说的做  也许你还能拿回来
Do exactly what I say and you might get it back.
但如果他们没有安然无恙地离开这
But if they don't walk out of here alive,
我会通知你名单上所有的客户
Every client on your list will be notified
你把他们的钱都弄不见了
That you've lost all their money.
到时我就不必杀你了
Then I won't have to kill you.
你的客户们自然会来杀你
Your clients will do that for me.
行动取消
The operation's burned.
把他们都杀了
Shoot them all.
爸爸
Dad!
法官  他没事吧
Judge, is he all right?
没事
Yeah.
那快带他回家
Then take him home.
我们去溜一圈吧
It's time we go for a little ride.
洛里默街3185号
3185 Lorimer.
科菲尔的房产
It's owned by Coldfield.
这是长发先生的车
And there's mr. Longhair's car.
纽约警局  有人在吗
NYPD, anybody home?
射门
Shoot, shoot!
进啦
Goal!
我们vs树  已经10比0啦
That's us, 10, trees, 0.
你真奇怪  爸爸
You're so weird, dad.
-再来一次吗  -来啊
- Do it again? - Let's go!
来吧
Here we go!
我没想到还能再见到你
I wasn't sure I'd ever see you again.
嗯  我不是很擅长...
Yeah, I'm, uh, not great
和人保持联系
At keeping in touch with people.
我不知道该怎么感谢你
I don't know how to thank you.
你什么都不用说
You don't need to say anything.
说实话我更希望你那样
I'd prefer it actually.
听着
Look...
我不知道你究竟是做什么的
I don't know exactly what you do,
也不知道你是怎么做的
Or how you're doing it.
但我知道要是被别人发现了
But I know that if people ever find out...
等到被别人发现了
When they find out...
我可没法保护你
There won't be anything I can do to protect you.
去和你儿子玩吧
Go play with your son.
他说了什么
What did he say?
他说让我们不必担心
That we don't need to worry.
以后他没准还能帮我们
He might even help us someday.
我听着你们的对话呢  里瑟先生
I was listening to your conversation, mr. Reese.
那我是听到了言外之意
And I was reading between the lines.
那我只能说  等时间来证明一切了
I suppose only time will tell which one of us is right.
谢谢你
Thank you.
你说什么
I beg your pardon?
谢谢你给我这份工作
For giving me a job.
试试这的火腿蛋松饼  里瑟先生
Try the eggs benedict, mr. Reese.
我几乎每次都会点
I've had them many times.
疑犯追踪 第1季 第5集
person.of.interest.s01e05.720p.hdtv.x264
字幕翻译：YYeTs人人影视